## Dripta S. Raychaudhuri

WCH 371, University of California

E-Mail: draychaudhuri@ece.ucr.edu Riverside CA 92521 Phone: +1 (951) 807-4062

Webpage: https://driptarc.github.io/

RESEARCH INTERESTS Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning

My interests lie in the scope of reducing supervision in deep learning systems. Along these lines, my research includes few-shot target re-identification, weakly supervised learning from videos and improving sample efficency in deep reinforcement learning algorithms.

**EDUCATION** 

University of California, Riverside, CA, USA

Sept 2018 - Present

PhD, Electrical and Computer Engineering Advisor: Dr. Amit K. Roy-Chowdhury

GPA: 3.97/4.0

Jadavpur University, Kolkata, WB, India

Aug. 2014 - June 2018

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Telecommunications Engineering

Advisor: Dr. Ananda S. Chowdhury

GPA: 9.37/10.00

EXPERIENCE

Research intern

June 2020 - Present Cambridge, MA, USA

Mitsubishi Electric Research Lab (MERL)

Advisor: Dr. Jeroen van Baar

• Transfer reinforcement learning

Graduate Student Researcher

April 2019 - Present

University of California, Riverside

**Advisor:** Dr. Amit K. Roy-Chowdhury

• Reducing supervision in visual recognition models

- Cross-domain adaptation of policies using imitation learning

- Few-shot/semi-supervised learning of re-identification models

WISE Research Intern

Video Computing Group

May 2017 - July 2017

DAAD:German Academic Exchange Service

University of Hildesheim

Advisor: Dr. Dr. Lars Schmidt-Thieme

• Channel masking for multivariate time series shapelets: An algorithm for classifying multivariate time series via a shapelet learning scheme using channel masks to automatically discount noisy channels.

Undergraduate Student Researcher

Aug. 2017 - June 2018 Jadavpur University

Imaging, Vision & Pattern Recognition Group

Advisor: Dr. Ananda S. Chowdhury

• Segmentation of aortic vessels: A level set based technique for identification and segmentation of aortic media-adventitia from fetal ultrasound images

**PUBLICATIONS** 

- Raychaudhuri, D.S. and Roy-Chowdhury, A.K., 2020. Exploiting Temporal Coherence for Self-Supervised One-shot Video Re-identification. European Conference on Computer Vision 2020
- Wang, X., Paul, S., Raychaudhuri, D.S., Liu, M., Wang, Y. and Roy-Chowdhury, A.K., 2020. Learning Person Re-identification Models from Videos with Weak Supervision. Under review
- Raychaudhuri, D.S., Grabocka, J. and Schmidt-Thieme, L., 2017. Channel masking for multivariate time series shapelets. arXiv preprint arXiv:1711.00812.

HONORS & AWARDS

• Dean's Distinguished Fellowship Award, University of California, Riverside

## $\bullet$ DAAD-WISE Fellowship Award, Research intern

## GRADUATE COURSEWORK

 $\bullet$  Probabilistic Graphical Models  $\bullet$  Introduction to Deep Learning  $\bullet$  Advanced Computer Vision  $\bullet$  Machine Learning  $\bullet$  Information Theory  $\bullet$  Stochastic Processes  $\bullet$  State & Parameter Estimation Theory  $\bullet$  Convex Optimization  $\bullet$  Mathematical Methods in EE  $\bullet$  Sparse Signal Processing

## $\begin{array}{c} \text{COMPUTER} \\ \text{SKILLS} \end{array}$

Python, Java, C, PyTorch, Matlab, OpenCV, sklearn